what are you looking
看什么啊
I’ve never seen someone use the toilet before.
没看过上厕所啊
Does Li Yi have any clues?
李义那边有线索了吗
Huang Shipeng hasn't made any progress here yet
黄仕鹏这儿还没进展
Is there any progress there?
你那儿呢 有进展吗
Conger is on time every day
聪儿每天都准时准点地
Follow the same route to and from school
按照同样的路线上下学
I have been observing her for several days
我观察她好几天了
It's half past five every day
每天都是五点半
Pass that intersection on time
准时经过那个路口
Although student life
虽然学生的生活
Very regular indeed
确实很有规律
But she's too precise
但她也太精确了
Just like clockwork
就跟上了发条一样
just like
就好像
Like something
好像什么
You finally started to doubt her
你总算开始怀疑她了
I'm coming
来了来了
coming
来了
Ms. Li
李女士
Why are you here again?
你怎么又来了
I want to talk to Cong'er again, is it okay?
我想再跟聪儿谈谈 可以吗
Mom, it's okay
妈 没事的
Thanks
谢谢
You can play chess?
你会下象棋啊
I was having sex with myself just now
我刚才在和自己下
Let's have a plate then
那来一盘吧
I lost
我输了
Do you want another plate?
要不要再来一盘
elder sister
姐姐
You probably didn't come here just to play chess, right?
你来应该不是为了下棋的吧
Why did you lose to me on purpose?
为什么故意输给我
Cong'er
聪儿
I came here to ask you something
我来是想问你一些事情
About you getting lost
关于你走丢的事情
Do you remember the day you disappeared?
你还记得自己走失那天吗
What about what happened after the loss?
那走失以后的事情呢
When was the will made?
遗嘱到底什么时候立
Every time I see that android
我每次看到那个仿生人
I feel hairy all over
都觉得浑身发毛
Cong'er
聪儿
If you find it difficult
如果你觉得困难的话
we can
我们可以
I do not remember
我不记得了
After returning to my parents
回到爸爸妈妈身边以后
I only dream about it occasionally
我只是偶尔会梦到
some fragmentary fragments
一些零碎的片段
I really can’t remember the specifics.
具体的我真的记不清了
elder sister
姐姐
Feel sorry
抱歉
Your life seems to have always been very regular.
你的生活好像一直都很规律
Dad said I should have a sense of time
爸爸说我要有时间观念
For example, let’s say you’re after school
那比如说你放了学
Will you occasionally go to a friend’s house to play?
会不会偶尔去朋友家玩
Or participate in some school extracurricular activities
或者参加一些学校的课外活动
Because I'm in sixth grade now
因为现在在上六年级
I'm going to be a junior high school student soon.
马上要小升初了
There is a lot of homework to do
有很多作业都要做
good
好
last question
最后一个问题
I used to work at your father's place
之前在你爸爸那里工作的
Uncle Li Yi
李义叔叔
have you seen him lately
你最近见过他吗
No
没有
When I was chatting with Cong'er, I discovered that
我跟聪儿聊天的时候发现
Her impressions of being lost
她对走失期间的印象
Very blurry
非常的模糊
She can only remember fragments
她只能记得零碎的片段
android memory
仿生人的记忆
Originally composed of fragmented fragments
本来就是由支离破碎的片段
consist of
组成的
Huang Conger had this reaction
黄聪儿有这种反应
It's also normal
也是正常的
With this memory
有了这段记忆
On the contrary, it better shapes the cornerstone of her personality.
反而更好地塑造她的人格基石
Let her cherish her current parents
让她珍惜现在的父母
What you said makes sense
你说得都很有道理
But I always feel
可是我总觉得
We can't just rely on these
我们不能仅凭这些
I concluded that Huang Conger is an android
就断定黄聪儿是仿生人
Then start from the beginning
那就从头查起
From the missing case of Huang Conger
就从黄聪儿走失案
look
你看
The real Huang Conger
真正的黄聪儿
was found five years ago
在五年前被找到了
But six years ago
可是六年前
Huang Shipeng started to fake
黄仕鹏就开始假冒
Her identity information
她的身份信息了
That is to say
也就是说
Huang Shipeng in Huang Conger
黄仕鹏在黄聪儿
before being reported
被报道出来之前
Just know this case
就知道这个案子
Today you continue to stare at Huang Conger
今天你继续盯着黄聪儿
I'm going to the police station
我去趟警局
excuse me
打扰了
Who is Police Officer He Yonghe?
哪位是何勇何警官
What do you want from him?
你找他什么事啊
I am bright-eyed Cheng Nuo
我是明眸的程诺
I would like to ask Officer He some questions.
想问一下何警官一些问题
Officer He has passed away
何警官已经去世了
died
去世了
right
对
died five years ago
五年前去世的
when discovered
发现的时候
It’s already terminal cancer
已经是癌症晚期了
He continued to work for a while
他还坚持工作了一段时间
Then let me ask you
那我问一下您
Do you know this person?
认不认识这个人
Or did Officer He ever mention him to you?
或者何警官有没有向你提过他
do not know
不认识
This man said that Officer He saved his daughter
这个人说何警官救过他女儿
Contact details are also provided
还提供了联系方式
But later we checked
但是后来我们查证
he is lying
他是在撒谎
Just don't know
只是不知道
How did he meet Officer He?
他是怎么认识的何警官
unfathomable understanding
深不可测的理解
Do you have any here?
那你们这边有没有
What about Officer He’s early police record?
早期何警官的出警记录呢
This is the application form. Please take a look.
这是申请单 您看一下
Wait a minute I need to verify
稍等 我需要核实一下
follow me
跟我来
Thanks for your hard work
辛苦了
Come and put it here
来 放这儿
These are all police records filed
这些全部都是备案的出警记录
Officer He's should be inside.
何警官的应该在里边
Trouble
麻烦了
You look first
你先看着
Cong'er
聪儿
elder sister
姐姐
Do you think what is said here is true?
你觉得这上面说的是真的吗
Androids harm society
仿生人危害社会
distorted moral values
扭曲道德观
Escape from reality
让人逃避现实
Shouldn't exist at all
根本就不应该存在
Cong'er
聪儿
This is just the view of some people
这只是一部分人的看法
What about Uncle Li Yi?
那李义叔叔呢
What did he do wrong
他做错了什么事
You want to catch him
你们要抓他
This matter is very complicated
这件事情很复杂
elder sister
姐姐
Why do you have to be at the school gate every day?
你为什么每天都要在学校门口
Stare at me
盯着我呀
elder sister
姐姐
Do you really want to arrest me?
你真的想把我抓起来吗
give me some time
你给我一点时间
Can you listen to me and slowly explain it to you?
你听我慢慢解释给你听 好吗
I am going home
我要回家了
Mom and dad are still waiting for me to eat
爸爸妈妈还在等我吃饭
Congconger
聪 聪儿
You didn’t just call me out for a late-night snack, did you?
你不会就是喊我出来吃宵夜的吧
sit
坐
So Huang Shipeng called the police
所以黄仕鹏报警
Not because I lost my daughter
不是因为丢了女儿
It's because I picked one up
是因为捡到了一个
wandering little girl
流浪的小女孩
this little girl
这小女孩
That's Huang Conger
就是黄聪儿
The day before yesterday when I was following Huang Shipeng
前天我跟踪黄仕鹏的时候
Have seen this man
见过这个男人
The money Huang Shipeng withdrew
黄仕鹏取的钱
It's all for him
都是给他的
Huang Shipeng was blackmailed by Cong'er's biological father
黄仕鹏在被聪儿的生父勒索
Cong'er's household registration
聪儿的户籍
Registered when she was four years old
在她四岁的时候才登记
Said he was biological father
说是生父
Maybe just her buyer
也许只是她的买家
As long as we don't say
只要我们不说
They can still live their own lives
他们照样可以过自己的日子
If the truth is revealed
如果揭开真相的话
It's like tearing this family apart
就等于拆散这个家
you are worried about them
你在担心他们
But blackmail is a thing
可是勒索这种事情
Appeared once
出现了一次
It will definitely happen a second time
就一定会出现第二次
We just have to find out the truth
我们只有查明真相
Only then can we really help Huang Shipeng’s family
才能真的帮到黄仕鹏一家
Now what
那现在怎么办
Just this piece of paper
光凭这一张纸
It doesn't constitute evidence at all
根本构成不了证据
Then they must admit this with their own mouths
那他们必须亲口承认这个事情
How can it be
怎么可能
Huang Shipeng has absolutely no need to cooperate with us
黄仕鹏完全没有必要配合我们
we have to help them
我们得帮他们
Just use the way you used
就用你用过的方式
What are you doing? Why are you here again?
你们干什么 你们怎么又来了
What are you doing?
干什么呀你们
Cong'er
聪儿
Shipeng Shipeng stopped them
仕鹏 仕鹏拦着他们呀
After injecting you with the medicine
给你注射完药剂以后
Are you an android?
你是不是仿生人
We'll find out soon
我们很快就会知道了
But if you really are
可如果你真的是
Your parents will be guilty of hiding the androids
你的父母就会因为藏匿仿生人
and be punished
而受到处罚
If you tell us the truth now
你如果现在跟我们说出真相
It won't bother them
就不会连累到他们
Cong'er
聪儿
dad
爸爸
Mother
妈妈
Cong'er
聪儿
You are an android and also my daughter
你是仿生人也是我女儿
Dad goes to apply to Mingmou
爸爸去跟明眸申请
Our family must be together
我们一家人一定要在一起
In order not to be discovered, Cong'er
聪儿为了不被识破
I searched a lot of information about bionic people.
查询了很多仿生人资料
She has been there for so many years
她这么多年
Haven't left this home yet
都没有离开这个家
You should have given her a lot of security
你们应该给了她很多安全感
Why does Cong'er live with you?
为什么聪儿会跟你们在一起生活
six years ago
六年前
Why is it you again?
怎么又是你啊
What to eat, eat, go quickly, go quickly
吃什么吃 赶紧走 赶紧走
Don't affect my business
别影响我做生意
Really
真是
If you want to eat, ask your parents to buy it.
要吃让你爸妈来买啊
Leave quickly
赶紧走啊
don't affect me
别影响我
Brother Peng is here
鹏哥 来了
Same old thing
老样子啊
okay
好嘞
Leave quickly
赶紧走啊
Children, come and sit
小朋友 来坐
The boss will add another noodle
老板 再加一份面
okay
好嘞
Sit, sit, sit
坐坐坐
No chili for one portion
一份不要辣椒啊
okay
好嘞
Here you go, eat slowly
来了 您慢吃啊
Come, come, come
来来来
Eat
吃啊
Recently
最近一段时间
I can always see her
我总能看到她
That noodle stall near where I work
在我工作那附近那个面摊儿
Pick up other people's leftovers
捡别人吃剩的东西
See it almost every day
几乎每天都能看到
Shipeng
仕鹏
It's this little girl
就是这个小女孩
Have you found her parents?
找到她父母了吗
found it
找到了
He said he would be here soon
说是一会儿就赶过来了
What's your name, kid?
小朋友 你叫什么名字
Oh my God
天呐
Shipeng
仕鹏
This hurt
这伤
She said she accidentally fell it
她说是自己不小心摔的
Fallen
摔的
The landlady is here
老板娘在啊
I want two noodles today
今天要两份面
Okay, Brother Huang
好嘞 黄哥
You ran out again by yourself
你又自己跑出来了
Where are your parents?
你爸爸妈妈呢
Didn't the police find her parents that day?
那天警察不是找到她父母了吗
This problem has not been solved either.
这问题也没解决呀
Take a look at this child
你瞅瞅这孩子身上
New injuries and old injuries
新伤旧伤的
Meeting his parents today
今天见着他爸妈
I have to ask what's going on
我得好好问问怎么回事
Don't be anxious first
你先别着急嘛
Which one is your home, kid?
哪个是你家啊 小朋友
This way
这边
This one
这个啊
Is this your home?
这个是你家吗
That
那
Oh my God
天呐
this
这
What kind of parents are these?
这什么父母呀
yes
对啊
This is so irresponsible
太不负责任了这个
Auntie, don't knock on the door
阿姨 别敲门
Never knock on the door
千万不要敲门
my parents
我爸爸妈妈
Don't let me talk to strangers
不让我和陌生人说话
Otherwise they will beat me
要不然他们会打我的
You go back first
你们先回去吧
I can go in by myself
我自己一个人能进去的
this
这
Okay, okay, let's go
行行行 咱们走吧
I'll go to the police station another day to report the situation.
改天再去警局反映一下情况
That kid
那个 小朋友
Are you sure this is your home?
你确定这是你家啊
That uncle and aunt are gone
那叔叔阿姨走了
That's it
那这样
Don't you know
你不是知道
Where does your uncle work?
你叔叔在哪儿工作吗
If you have any difficulties, what can I do?
你要是有什么困难有什么事
Just go find your uncle
就去找你叔叔
OK
好不好
good
好
obedient
听话
Then let's go
那我们走了啊
let's go
走吧走吧
Let's go, let's go
走吧走吧走吧
You and your wife
你们夫妻俩
Why are you meddling in so many other things?
管那么多闲事干嘛呀
let me tell you
我跟你说
That kid is an android
那孩子就是个仿生人
Throw it on the street and no one wants it
扔到大街上都没人要
Even if it’s an android
就算是仿生人
You can't ignore such a small child.
那么小的孩子也不能不管啊
Otherwise, you should be a good person and take it to the end.
要不你就好人当到底
you give me money
你给我钱
I will kindly sell this daughter to you.
这个女儿 我就好心卖给你了
What are you talking about?
你说的这是什么话
What police
什么警察
for a child
对于一个孩子来说
Are legal parents important?
是法律上的父母重要
What's more important is loving his parents?
还是爱他的父母重要啊
Isn't this a thing?
这不是一件事吗
Let me tell you
要我说呀
the most important is
最重要的是
Don’t commit sin if your adopted son is barren
养子不育 就莫作孽
You said they are still okay?
你说他们这还算是
Be a parent?
为人父母吗
Just know that you are enjoying yourself
就知道自己享乐
Don't care about the children at all
对孩子一点都不管不顾的
You also saw the injuries on the child
你也看见那孩子身上的伤了
That must be man-made
那肯定是人为的呀
Do not be angry
别生气了
so many years
这么多年了
Neither of us wants a child.
咱们俩想要个孩子都要不了
People here have children
人家这有孩子的
Don’t know how to cherish it yet
还不知道珍惜
or
要不
Take her to our home
把她接到咱家
Pick us up
接咱们家
That
那
Is it illegal?
犯法的吧
Come on, come on, come on, take a look
快来快来 来 快看看
like or not
喜不喜欢
This will be your room from now on
以后就是你的房间
As long as you are willing to
只要你愿意
Live with us from now on
今后就跟我们一起生活
Sit on and give it a try
坐上试一试
How about it
怎么样
and this
还有这个
Whether you are an android or not
不管你是不是仿生人
Dad will love you just as much
爸爸都会一样爱你的
We have been a family for a long time
咱们早就是一家人了
She has it all planned
她都计划好了
This is the ticket and luggage
这是车票和行李
If we hadn't suddenly come over today
如果不是我们今天突然过来
she probably
她很可能
left already
已经走了
Silly boy
傻孩子
How could mother possibly let you wander again?
妈妈怎么可能再去让你流浪呢
Officer Chen
陈警官
good
好
Come in
进来
Officer Chen, what do you mean?
陈警官 你这什么意思啊
stand still
站好
why do you want to come here
你们为什么要来这里
I gave you all the money I saved
我存的钱都给你们了
You promised me you wouldn't show up again
你们答应过我不会再出现的
Why do you want to lie?
你们为什么要骗人
Cong'er
聪儿
Conger, what are you talking about?
聪儿 你在说什么呢
what on earth did you do
你到底做什么了
dad
爸爸
They don't just ask you for money
他们不仅找你要钱
Still asking me for money
还找我要钱
You promise not to tell on me
你保证不要告发我
this is all my money
这是我所有的钱
You scum
你们这些人渣
What are you doing?
干什么呢
The police are still here
警察还在这儿呢
Zhao Meng Chen Ying
赵猛 陈颖
Do you know this kid?
这个小孩认识吗
what relationship
什么关系
I'm so stupid after taking drugs that I don't know
吸毒吸傻了呀 不认识
say
说话
I bought the android
是我买的仿生人
Don’t you know that smuggling androids is illegal?
你不知道走私仿生人是犯法的吗
My old man said
我家老爷子说了
Whoever has children will give the inheritance to them
谁有孩子就把遗产给谁
Who knew it was so hard to pull a child?
谁知道拉扯个孩子这么费劲
I don't want to care anymore
我是不想管了
you all heard it
你们都听到了
This pair of scum
这对人渣
Will just throw Cong'er on the street
只会把聪儿扔在大街上
I won't let Cong'er go with you again.
我不会再让聪儿跟你们走的
Will not
不会的
Your relationship is now illegal.
现在你们的关系不合法
You and Huang Conger
你们和黄聪儿
separate for a while
暂时分开一段时间
Our police will communicate with Mingmou
我们警方会和明眸
Let's handle this properly together
一起妥善处理这件事
Cong'er
聪儿
You pack your luggage
你收拾一下行李
Let’s take a look back at our bright eyes first.
先跟我们回明眸吧
elder sister
姐姐
I'll do it myself
我自己来吧
Can you play a game of chess with me again?
你能再陪我下一盘棋吗
OK
好啊
Cong'er
聪儿
They will be back soon
他们很快就会回来的
I will also apply to the headquarters
我也会向总部申请
Let you stay with them
让你留在他们身边
I know
我知道
Mom and dad are just not here temporarily
爸爸妈妈只是暂时不在
I will stay in Mingmou obediently
我会乖乖地待在明眸
Wait until they come out
等他们出来了
Let's go home together again
我们再一起回家
Although this home
虽然这个家
It was a lie from the beginning
一开始就是一个谎言
but it works for me
但它对我来说
It's the real home
就是真正的家
elder sister
姐姐
You are a good guy
你是好人
Uncle Li Yi is also a good person
李义叔叔也是好人
Can you not arrest him?
你们可以不抓他吗
do you know where he is
你知道他在哪儿吗
Is he an android?
他是仿生人吗
We'll have to wait until we find him to be sure.
得等找到他之后才能确定
Did he say anything to you?
他跟你说过什么吗
No
没有
Uncle always talks very little
叔叔每次的话都很少
Put down the gift and leave
放下礼物就走了
What gift?
礼物 什么礼物
That's it
就是这个呀
This is what I found that day
那天的找到了 就是这
Just watch this video
就这个视频 你看一下
I bought this chess piece that day.
那天就是买的这个棋 这个
Is there any record of his payment?
他的付款记录还有吗
There should be
应该有吧
Is it okay if I look for it this way?
这样 我找找看行吗
Thank you
谢谢你
Tina
蒂娜
This is the latest work progress of our department
这是我们部门最近的工作进展
correct
对了
Minister doubts previous shantytown raids
部长怀疑之前棚户区搜查行动
Something slipped through the net
有漏网之鱼
You can check again
你们可以再查查
Mingmo has conducted raids in shantytowns
明眸在棚户区有过搜查行动
when
什么时候啊
two years ago
两年前
At that time, many illegal androids were arrested.
当时还抓了很多违法的仿生人呢
Do you know where I can find relevant information?
你知道哪里有相关的资料吗
Then I'll send it to you
那我发给你啊
Thanks
谢谢
that shantytown
那个棚户区
I can't find it online
我在网上搜不到
Any information about androids
任何关于仿生人的资料
what happened
到底发生过什么
specific
具体
I'm not so sure either
我也不太清楚